This program, we'll print out a birth certificate is a valid ID.
في هذا البرنامج، سنطبع عبارة A birth certificate is a valid ID.
With these boolean values,
بواسطة هذه القيم المنطقية،
our computer will go through our code line by line.
سيمرّ الحاسوب بالكود سطراً تلو سطر.
First it sees our IF statement,
سيرى أولاً عبارة if،
and since passport is false,
وبما أن passport قيمتها false،
it passes by this block of code and goes to our next else if.
فإنه سيتخطّى كتلة التعليمات البرمجية هذه وينتقل إلى عبارة else if التالية.
This else if checks if birth certificate is true.
تتحققّ عبارة else if هذه مما إذا كانت شهادة الميلاد هي true.
It is, so it executes this block of code and
إنها كذلك، فيتم تنفيذ كتلة التعليمات البرمجية هذه
prints out a birth certificate is a valid ID.
وطباعة عبارة A birth certificate is a valid ID.
Then it sees that there's only an else if and an else remaining.
ثم يرى الحاسوب أنه لم يتبقَ سوى عبارة else if وعبارة else.
And since one else if block of code has already been executed,
بما أنه تم تنفيذ كتلة تعليمات برمجية واحدة لـelse if بالفعل،
it can ignore these other blocks,
فيمكنه بالتالي تجاهل كتل التعليمات البرمجية الأخرى هذه،
even though the condition for driver's license is also true.
حتى لو أن حالة عبارة driversLicense هي true أيضاً.
And it will skip down to the end of this last else.
وسيتخطى الحاسوب ذلك وصولاً إلى نهاية عبارة else الأخيرة هذه.
And this is all that will print out.
وهذا هو كل ما سيطبعه.
So this person will successfully get a library card.
إذن، سيحصل هذا الشخص على بطاقة مكتبة بنجاح.
So for a series of else ifs and an else,
بالنسبة إلى سلسلة من عبارات else if وعبارة else،
only one block of code can be executed at a time,
يمكن تنفيذ كتلة تعليمات برمجية واحدة فقط في كل مرة،
which every statement has its test condition met first.
وهي أول عبارة تتحقق حالة اختبارها.
Which in this case was the birth certificate tests condition.
وفي هذه الحالة، كانت حالة اختبار شهادة الميلاد.
So using ifs and else ifs in combination can be really
يمكن أن يكون استخدام عبارات if وelse if معاً مفيداً
useful for programming decision making with lots of unique pathways to take.
في برمجة اتخاذ القرار مع وجود العديد المسارات المميزة التي يمكن سلكها.